Stephen E. Malawista papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Submission of manuscripts for publication, Series IV
  - Reviews, Subseries 2
    - 1980s
      - Reviews 21R, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 2)
        Malawista, S.E. and Steere, A.C. "Lyme disease." In: Prognosis: Contemporary Outcomes of Disease. J.F. Fries and G.E. Ehrlich, eds. Charles Press, Bowie, MD, l98l, pp. 354-35? [missing in CV]
        Correspondence, 1979-1980, and drafts.
      - Reviews 22R, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 3)
        Malawista, S.E. and Steere, A.C. "Viral Arthritis, in: Textbook of Rheumatology, W.N. Kelley, E.D. Harris, Jr., S. Ruddy, and C.B. Sledge, eds. W.B. Saunders, Philadelphia, l98l, pp. l586-l60l.
      - Reviews 23R, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 4)
        Malawista, S.E. and Steere, A.C. "Lyme Disease," in: The Merck Manual, l4th Edition. Robert Berkow and J.H. Talbot, eds. Merck Sharp & Dohme Research Laboratories, Rahway, NJ, l982, pp. ll90-ll92.
        Correspondence, 1979-1980, 1983, drafts, notes. The 1983 correspondence concerns revisions for the third printing of the Manual.
      - Reviews 24R, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 5)
        Malawista, S.E. and Hardin John A. "Rheumatoid Arthritis," in: Clinical Dermatology, D.J. Demis, R.G. Crounse, R.L. Dobson and J. McGuire, eds. Harper & Row, Philadelphia, l983.
        Revision of a chapter that Malawista had previously written. Folder contains correspondence, drafts of changes to previous version, and unpaginated printed version. "Vol. 1 Unit 5-14."
      - Reviews 25R, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 6)
        Malawista, S.E. "Artritis relacionada con cristales," in: Inflamacion y Tratamiento Antiinflamatorio en Reumatologia, ed. Gabor Katona. Mansion Galindo, Queretaro, Mexico, l982, ll5-l29.
        Translation into Spanish of "Arthritis associated with crystals." Folder contains two drafts and photographs.
      - Reviews 26R, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 7)
        Steere, A.C. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme Disease," in: Textbook of Rheumatology, 2nd edition. William N. Kelley, Edward D. Harris, Jr., Shaun Ruddy, and Clement B. Sledge, eds. W.B. Saunders, Philadelphia, l983, pp. 1557-1563.
        Correspondence, 1982-1983, drafts, photographs.
      - Reviews 27E, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 8)
        Malawista, S.E. "Rheumatology," in: l983 Year Book of Medicine. D.E. Rogers, R.M. Des Pres, M.J. Cline, E. Braunwald, N.J. Greenberger, Philip K. Bondy, F.H. Epstein, and S. Malawista, eds. Year Book Medical Publishers, Inc., Chicago, l983, pp. 6l9-668. Malawista listed this publication as 27E because he served as an editor of the volume.
        Correspondence, 1982 and n.d., and drafts.
      - Reviews 28R, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 9)
        Steere, A.C. and Malawista, S.E. "The Epidemiology of Lyme disease," in: Current Topics in Rheumatology: Epidemiology of the Rheumatic Diseases. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference. R.C. Lawrence and L.E. Schulman, eds. Gower Medical Publishing Limited, New York, 1983, pp. 33-42.
      - Reviews 32R, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 10)
        Malawista, S.E. "Infectious Arthritis," in: Cecil Textbook of Medicine, 17th ed. James B. Wyngaarden and Lloyd H. Smith, eds. W.B. Saunders Co., Philadelphia, pp. 1922-1924, 1985.
        Correspondence, 1983-1985, drafts, and printed "instructions to Contributors."
      - Reviews 33R, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 11)
        Steere, A.C. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme Disease," in: Arthritis and Allied Conditions, 10th edition. D.J. McCarty, ed. Lea & Febiger, Philadelphia, 1985, pp. 1713-1722.
        Drafts and corrections to proof.
      - Reviews 34R, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 12)
        Steere, A.C. and Malawista, S.E. "Viral Arthritis," in: Arthritis and Allied Conditions, l0th edition. D.J. McCarty, ed. Lea & Febiger, Philadelphia, l985, pp. 1697-1712.
      - Reviews 35R, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 13)
        Steere, A.C. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme Disease," in: Principles and Practice of Infectious Diseases. G.L. Mandell, R.G. Douglas, Jr. and J.E. Bennett, eds. John Wiley and Sons, Inc., New York, 1985, pp. 1343-1349.
        Correspondence, 1983, draft.
      - Reviews 39R, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 1)
        Malawista, S.E. and Steere, A.C. "Lyme disease: infectious in origin, rheumatic in expression," in: Advances in Internal Medicine, G.H. Stollerman, ed. Year Book Medical Publishers, Inc., l986 pp. l47-166.
      - Reviews 40R, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 2)
        Malawista, S.E. and Steere, A.C. "Lyme disease," In: Proceedings of the XVI International Congress of Rheumatology (ILAR), Sydney, Australia, May l985. Elsevier Science Publishers (Amsterdam), pp. 2l7-222, l985.
        Correspondence, 1984-1985, draft, reprint.
      - Reviews 47R, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 3)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: The Merck Manual, 15th Edition, R. Berkow, ed. Merck Sharp & Dohme Research Laboratories, Rahway, NJ 1987, pp. 1251-1253.
        Correspondence, 1983-1986, 1990, changes made to previous edition.
      - Reviews 49R, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 4)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Cecil Textbook of Medicine, 18th Edition. Ed. Wyngaarden, J.B., Smith, Jr., L.H. W.B. Saunders (Philadelphia), 1726-1729, 1988.
        Correspondence, 1986-1989, draft, proof, figures. This is the first edition for which Malawista wrote the article without Steere.
      - Reviews 51R, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 5)
        Schoen, Robert T. and Malawista, S.E. "Treatment of Lyme disease," The Medical Letter 30: 65-68, 1988.
        Correspondence, 1988, drafts, and reprint.
      - Reviews 52R, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 6)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Arthritis and Allied Conditions. D.J. McCarty, ed. Philadelphia: Lea & Febiger, 1988, 1955-1965.
      - Reviews 53R, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 7)
        Malawista, S.E. "The many faces of Lyme disease" (Davidson Lecture), Proc. Royal Coll. Physicians Edin. 405-411, 1989.
        Stanley Davidson Lecture presented by Malawista at the Royal College of Physicians, Edinburgh, in 1988, and published in the Proceedings. Folder contains correspondence, 1988-1989, and a draft.
      - Reviews 55R, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 8)
        Craft, J.E. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," Current Opinion in Infectious Diseases, 2:218-222, 1989.
      - Reviews 56R, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 9)
        Malawista, S.E. "Pathogenesis of Lyme disease," Rheumatol. Int. 9:233-235, 1989.
    - 1990s
      - Reviews 58R, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 10)
        Rahn, D.W. and Malawista, S.E. "Clinical judgment in Lyme disease," Hospital Practice 25:39-56, 1990.
      - Reviews 63R, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 11)
        Malawista, S.E. "Diagnosis of Lyme disease: Clinical judgment remains crucial," in Proceedings, Asian-Pacific League against Rheumatism (APLAR) 1992, A.R. Nasution, J. Darmawan, H. Isbagio eds. Churchill Livingstone, Japan, pp. 269-272.
      - Reviews 64R, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 12)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: The Merck Manual, 16th Edition. Berkow, R. and Fletcher, A.J. eds. Merck Sharp & Dohme Research Laboratories, Rahway, NJ. 1992, pp. 155-157.
        Correspondence, 1989-1993, drafts, and a Merck press release, May 14, 1993, on Malawista's contribution sent to Malawista for review.
      - Reviews 65R, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 13)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Cecil's Textbook of Medicine, 19th Edition. Wyngaarden, J.B., Smith, Jr., L.H., Bennett, J.C., eds. W.B. Saunders, Philadelphia, 1992, pp. 1772-1777.
        Correspondence, 1989-1993, drafts, proof. Originally the first author was Daniel W. Rahn, but the article was finally authored just by Malawista. Included is some correspondence concerning the 20th edition, which is not on Malawista's CV.
      - Reviews 66R, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 14)
        Malawista, S.E. "Infectious Arthritis," In: Cecil's Textbook of Medicine, 19th Edition. Wyngaarden, J.B., Smith, Jr., L.H., Bennett, J.C., eds. W.B. Saunders, Philadelphia, 1992, pp. 1520-1521.
        Correspondence, 1989-1990, drafts, notes.
      - Reviews 68R, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 15)
        Malawista, S.E., Trock, D.H., and Edelson, R.L. "Photopheresis for Rheumatoid Arthritis," in Antigen and Clone-Specific Immunoregulation, R.L. Edelson, ed. Proc. N.Y. Acad. Sci. 636:217-226, 1992.
      - Reviews 69R, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 16)
        Rahn, Daniel W. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Arthritis and Allied Conditions, 12th Edition, D.J. McCarty and W.J. Koopman, eds. Lea & Febiger, Philadelphia, 1993, pp. 2067-2079.
        Correspondence, 1990-1991, edited proof, reprint.
      - Reviews 71R, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 1)
        Malawista, S.E., Van Blaricom, G., and Chevance de Boisfleury, A. "Cytokineplasts and U-cytoplasts from human polymorphonuclear leukocytes: Role of granule-poor motile fragments in the analysis of cell physiology," Blood Cells 18:63-80, 1993.
        Folder includes an informal discussion on cytokineplasts by Malawista, Bessis, Chevance, Hakim, Maxfield, and others, May 17, 1992.
      - Reviews 72R, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 2)
        Schoen, R.T. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme Arthritis, in: Cliniguide to Rheumatology, ed. Gerald Weissmann. DellaCorte, New York, 3[4]: 1-7, 1994.
      - Reviews 75R, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 3)
        Montgomery, R.R. and Malawista, S.E. "Borrelia burgdorferi and the macrophage: Routine annihilation but occasional haven?" Parasitology Today 10:154-157, 1994. Correspondence 1993, images.
      - Reviews 80R, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 4)
        Malawista, S.E. (translator). "Remembrance of Professor Marcel Bessis (1917-1994), by Professor Jean Bernard, de l'Academie Française," Blood Cells, Molecules, and Diseases 21:152-155, 1995.
      - Reviews 82R, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 5)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Cecil's Textbook of Medicine, 20th Edition. Wyngaarden, J.B., Smith, Jr., L.H., Bennett, J.C., eds. W.B. Saunders, Philadelphia, 1996, pp. 1715-1720.
      - Reviews 83R, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 6)
        Bockenstedt, L.K. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme Disease," in: Clinical Immunology, Rich, R.R., ed. Mosby-Year Book, Inc., St. Louis, 1996, pp. 1234-1249.
      - Reviews 84R, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 7)
        Evans,J. and Malawista, S.E. Lyme Disease, in: Infectious Disease Teaching Atlas, Mandell, G.L., ed. Current Medicine, Philadelphia, 1997, pp.6.1-6.10.
      - Reviews 86R, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 8)
        Evans, J. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme Disease," in: Current Therapy in Adult Medicine 4th Edition, ed. Kassirer, J.P., and Greene, H.L., Mosby-Year Book, Inc., St. Louis, 1997, pp. 297-300.
      - Reviews 89E, 1998 (Box 36, Folder 9)
        Malawista, S.E. "Rheumatology," in: 1998 Year Book of Medicine. Cline, M.J., Frishman, W., and Greenberger, N.J., Klahr, S., Malawista, S.E., Mandell, G.L., Petty, T.L., and Utiger, R.D., eds. Mosby-Year Book, Inc., St. Louis, 1998, pp. 449-512.
      - Reviews 90R, 1998 (Box 36, Folder 10)
        Malawista, S.E., and de Boisfleury Chevance, A. "Fonctions de motilité des polynucléaires du sang humain: locomotion et chimiotactisme dans des systèmes simplifiés," Bull. Académie Nationale de Médecine 182:1011-1024, 1998.
      - Reviews 91R, 1999 (Box 36, Folder 11)
        Malawista, S.E., "Lyme disease," in The Merck Manual, 17th Edition. Berkow, R. and Fletcher, A.J. eds. Merck Sharp & Dohme Research Laboratories, Whitehouse Station, NJ., 1999, pp. 1189-1192.
      - Reviews 92E, 1999 (Box 36, Folder 12)
        Malawista, S.E. "Rheumatology." in: 1999 Year Book of Medicine. Bagdade, J.D., Barkin, J.S., Frishman, W.H., Jett, J.R., Klahr, S., Malawista, S.E., Mandell, G.L., McCallum, R.W., and Young, N.S., eds. Mosby-Year Book, Inc., St. Louis, pp. 1-79, 1999.
    - 2000s
      - Reviews 93R, 2001 (Box 36, Folder 13)
        Molad, Y., Cronstein, B.N., and Malawista, S.E., "Colchicine." In: Gout, Hyperuricemia, and Other Crystal-Associated Arthropathries. Smyth, C.J., and Holers, V.M., eds. Marcel Dekker, N.Y., 1999, pp. 193-204
      - Reviews 94E, 2000 (Box 36, Folder 14)
        Malawista, S.E. "Rheumatology" (30 editorials), in: 2000 Year Book of Medicine. Bagdade, J.D., Barkin, J.S., Frishman, W.H., Jett, J.R., Klahr, S., Loehrer, P.J., Malawista, S.E., Mandell, G.L., and Mazzaferri, E.L., eds. Mosby-Year Book, Inc., St. Louis, pp. 1-72, 2000.
      - Reviews 96R, 2000 (Box 36, Folder 15)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Cecil's Textbook of Medicine. 21st Edition. Goldman, L., and Bennett, J.C., eds. W.B. Saunders, Philadelphia, 2000, pp. 1757-1761.
      - Reviews 98R, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 1)
        Evans, J. and Malawista, S.E. "Lyme Disease," in: Current Therapy of Infectious Disease, 2nd Edition. Schlossberg, D., ed. Mosby, Inc., Philadelphia, pp. 638-642, 2001.
      - Reviews 99Ra, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 2)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Arthritis and Allied Conditions, 14th Edition. Koopman, W.J., ed. Lippincott Williams & Wilkins, Philadelphia, 2001, pp. 2321-2339.
      - Reviews 99Rb, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Reviews 103R, 2004 (Box 37, Folder 4)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Cecil's Textbook of Medicine, 22nd Edition. Goldman, L., and Ausiello, D., eds. W.B. Saunders, Philadelphia, 2004, pp. 1934-1939.
        Correspondence 2003-2004, changes, corrected page proofs.
      - Reviews 104R, 2005 (Box 37, Folder 5)
        Malawista, S.E. "Lyme disease," in: Arthritis and Allied Conditions, 15th Edition. Koopman WJ, Moreland LW, eds. Lippincott Williams & Wilkins, Philadelphia, 2005, pp. 2645-2664.
      - Reviews 105R, 2008 (Box 37, Folder 6)
        Evans, J. and Malawista S.E. "Lyme disease," in: C linical Infectious Disease, Schlossberg, D., ed., Cambridge University Press, New York, 2008 pp. 1127-2234.
  - Manuscripts not published or not included in list of publications., Subseries 3
    These files may include manuscripts later published under a variant title.
    - "Chapter on Rheumatoid Arthritis", 1966 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      This folder contains drafts and letters concerning obtaining copies of images. There is no correspondence with the publisher, though Malawista notes that the article was to be published in a new textbook on Dermatology to be published by Hoeber. This folder may relate to Reviews 7, 1972.
    - "Chapter on Gout", 1966 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      The chapter was for a textbook on dermatology to be published by Hoeber.
    - "Microtubules in Human Polymorphonuclear Leucocytes: Dissolution of Colchicine," letter to the Editor of Nature, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Robert H. Gifford and S.E. Malawista, "Characteristics of the Nitro-blue Tetrazolium Reaction in Human Granulocytes", 1969 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      Presumably rejected by the Journal of Clinical Investigation. See Articles 22, 1970, and Articles 34, 1972.
    - S.E. Malawista and A.C. Steere, paper on three cases of erythema chronica migrans, 1976 December 30 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      The paper on three cases of the condition in Americans who had visited Europe was rejected by Annals of Internal Medicine, but Steere and Malawista were asked instead to work with a dermatologist "to prepare an editorial note that would call attention to the emergence of erythema chronicum migrrans as a 'new' problem." The association of the skin lesion with Lyme arthritis would be part of the editorial note. Folder contains just the rejection letter from Edward Huth, M.D., editor of the journal.
    - S.E. Malawista and A.C. Steere, "Viral Arthritis," probably for Textbook of Rheumatology (1981), 1978 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      The folder contains the table of contents for "Textbook of Rheumatology" and drafts of the article, some dated 1978. The article was probably published in Textbook of Rheumatology, 1st ed., ed. William N. Kelley et al. Philadelphia: W.B. Saunders, 1981. Not in Malawista's CV.
    - Invitation to write a review on Lyme arthritis, not submitted, 1979-1982 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      Malawista was asked to write a review article on Lyme arthritis for the Bulletin on the Rheumatic Diseases in 1979. He agreed to do it but wanted to delay for a year. There is no article in this journal in Malawista's CV. File contains correspondence only.
    - P. L. Moore and S. E. Malawista, "Periodic Structures at the Granule-Phagocytic Vacuole Interface of Human Polymorphonuclear Leukocytes," rejected paper, 1980-1981 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      This paper was supposed to be sent to Anatomical Record by the first author, Patrick L. Moore. It does not appear in Malawista's CV.
    - "Lyme Disease: Immunogenetic Profile, Early Immune Response, and Subsequent Severity of Illness," rejected paper, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      Allen C. Steere, Robert J. Winchester, Allan Gibovsky, S.J. Waters, M. Fotino, and Stephen E. Malawista, "Lyme Disease: Immunogenetic Profile, Early Immune Response, and Subsequent Severity of Illness," rejected by New England Journal of Medicine, 1981.
    - "Grouped Projections at the Granule-Phagocytic Vacuole Interface," rejected paper, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      Patrick L. Moore and Stephen E. Malawista, "Grouped Projections at the Granule-Phagocytic Vacuole Interface in Human Polymorphonuclear Leukocytes," rejected by Blood Cells, 1981.
    - S.E. Malawista, G. Van Blaricom, and S. Cretella, "Lyme Disease," in Primer of Rheumatic Diseases published by the Arthritis Foundation, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      There were many editions of the Primer on Rheumatic Diseases. It is not clear which edition this article was published in. The correspondence and draft dates from 1982. The article is not on Malawista's CV.
    - S.E. Malawista, G. Van Blaricom, and S. Cretella, "Cytokineplasts from Human Blood and Polymorphonuclear Leukocytes," rejected article, 1984 July 5 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      Stephen E. Malawista, Gretchen Van Blaricom, and Stella B. Cretella, "Cytokineplasts from Human Blood Polymorphonuclear leukocytes: Lack of Oxidase Activity and Extended Functional Longevity," rejected by Blood.
      Folder contains correspondence with the editor, reviews, and drafts.
    - S.E. Malawista, M. Breitenstein, and G. Van Blaricom, "Heated Cell paper", ca. 1985 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      Stephen E. Malawista, Mary G. Breitenstein, and Gretchen von Blaricom, "Functional Evidence for Respiratory Burst Oxidase Activity in Azurophil Granules of Human Blood Polymorphonuclear Leukocytes (PMN): Studies with Heated Cells." There is no indication that this was published, but see Articles 93.
    - S.E. Malawista, "Lyme Disease", 1987 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      Possibly for the 11th edition of Daniel McCarty, ed., Arthritis and Allied Conditions. See letter from Malawista to McCarty, April 28, 1987, attached to manuscript. According to his CV, Malawista wrote articles for the 10th and 12th editions.
    - S.E. Malawista et al, "A Subgroup of Chronic Granulamatous Disease of Children with Associated Glutathione Peroxidase Deficiency", ca. 1987-1991 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      Manuscript by S.E. Malawista, Janet Oliver, Gretchen Van Blaricom, and John Curnutte, was set up for sending to a publisher, but there is no correspondence with editors. Includes a letter from Curnutte to Malawista, January 6, 1987.
    - S.E. Malawista, "Treatment of rheumatoid arthritis by extracorporeal photochemotherapy," rejected paper, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      Stephen E. Malawista, David Trock, and Richard Edelson, "Treatment of rheumatoid arthritis by extracorporeal photochemotherapy - A pilot study," submitted to New England Journal of Medicine, then to Annals of Internal Medicine, and finally to Arthritis and Rheumatism. Folder includes correspondence, reviews, and drafts.
    - Daniel W. Rahn and S.E. Malawista, "Lyme Disease," for update of Cecil Textbook of Medicine, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      The dates of the letter and drafts are 1990. This folder may relate to Reviews 61R.
    - Rabia Balicca, S.E. Malawista, and Ruth Montgomery, "Quantitative measure of killing B. burgdorferi by polymorphonuclear leukocytes in vitro", 1996 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      Submitted to Journal of Immunological Methods, but does not appear in Malawista's CV.
    - Leonard H. Sigal, et al, "Efficacy of OspA vaccine in prevention of Lyme disease", 1998 (Box 38, Folder 15)
      The article has many authors including Malawista. Its long title is "Multicenter efficacy trial of a prophylactic recombinant Borrelia burgdorferi Outer surface protein (OspA) vaccine for Lyme disease." This manuscript may relate to Article 131 on Malawista's CV.
      There is also correspondence on L.H. Sigal's paper, "Diagnostic and Management Pitfalls in Lyme Disease," rejected by Arthritis and Rheumatism in 1997.
    - Ruth Montgomery, S.E. Malawista, et al, "Oral restimulation of the murine response to Borrelia burgdorferi, the agent of Lyme disease", 2002 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      Two versions of the manuscript. Not in Malawista's CV.
    - R. Montgomery et al, "Stripping the Phagocytic Zipper: The Lyme Spirochete Fights Back," rejected paper, 2002-2003 (Box 38, Folder 17)
      This paper by Stephen E. Malawista, Anne de Boisfleury Chevance, and Ruth R. Montgomery, was submitted to Infection and Immunity and rejected. The authors responded to the reviews, but the article was still not accepted.
- Grant and contract proposals, Series V
  Folders contain proposals submitted to funding agencies, and possibly some correspondence with research colleagues, the Yale administration, and the granting agency. Grant proposals may contain Social Security numbers and salaries.
  - Major NIH grants: NIH R01 AR10493: "Biophysical Mechanisms in Leukocytes and Melanocytes", Subseries 1
    Biographical / Historical
    "Biophysical Mechanisms in Leukocytes and Melanocytes," was Stephen Malawista's main grant from the National Institutes of Health. It lasted under the same title for over 35 years until Malawista closed it out in 2008.
    This subseries is missing the original grant proposal but does include non-competitive continuations, renewals, requests for changes, correspondence with NIH officials, and related materials from 1975 to 2008. The number following R01 AR10493 corresponds to the number of years the grant was held.
    - NIH R01 AM10493, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      A renewal application. The original grant proposal has not been found.
    - NIH 2 R01 AM10493-17, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      Competitive renewal.
    - NIH 2 R01 AM10493-18, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - NIH 5 R01 AM10493-19, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - NIH 5 R01 AM10493-20, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - NIH 2 R01 AM10493-21, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - NIH R01 AR10493, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - NIH 2 R01 AM10493-21A1, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-22, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-23, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-24, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-25, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - NIH R01 AR10493, Part 1, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Malawista submitted a preliminary competitive renewal proposal in January 1992 and did not get as high a rating as he hoped. The next folder contains the revision submitted later in the year.
    - NIH R01 AR10493, Part 2, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - NIH R01 AR10493-26A2, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - NIH 2 R01 AR10493-27, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-28, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-29, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-30, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-31, 1997-1998 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      Preliminary review by an NIH ad hoc group of Malawista's competitive renewal.
    - NIH 2 R01 AR10493, 1998 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-32, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-33, 2001 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - NIH 5 R01 AR10493-34, 2002 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - NIH 2 R01 AR10493, 2003 (Box 41, Folder 1)